thepodcasthost.com 2019-02-05

# Our Privacy Policy

The Podcast Host Ltd. is committed to respecting the privacy rights of its visitors and users of this website. We created this Privacy Policy to give you confidence as you visit and use the website, and to demonstrate a commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy.

The Policy specifically outlines the types of information that we gather about you while you are using www.thepodcasthost.com, and the ways in which we use this information.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you may provide to us or that we may collect offline and/or through other means (for example, at a live event, via telephone, or through the mail).

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By visiting and using the Site, you agree that your use of our Site, and any dispute over privacy, is governed by this Privacy Policy. We endeavor to keep the information up to date and correct, we make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability with respect to the website or the information, products, services, or related graphics contained on the website for any purpose. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk.

We are not liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website. The Podcast Host Ltd. takes no responsibility and will not be liable for the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond our control.

## Information We Collect

We may collect and store personal or other information that you voluntarily supply to us online while using the Site. This Site only contacts individuals who specifically request that we do so or in the event that they have signed up to receive our free newsletters or have purchased one of our products. This Site collects personally identifying information from our users during online registration and online purchasing. Our servers automatically recognize visitors’ domain names and IP addresses (the number assigned to computers on the Internet). No personal information about you is revealed in this process.

We run Google Analytics as a data collection tool in order to measure the traffic volume, types and source. This is used for our own reference only, and includes some demographic data. A cookie may be used within this process to track your usage of this site.

## How We Use Information

We will not share your personal information with any third parties without your consent, except as necessary to provide you with the services offered by us or to comply with the law. Examples of such services include, but are not limited to, third parties providing email facilitation and hosting.

However, please note that if you leave the Site and purchase a product or service we promote, the company you purchase from will notify us of the purchase and may well include certain identifying information for you. We do not share this information with others.

For example, we use Amazon Affiliate links within many of the reviews on this website. This helps us to fund the free content and advice we provide. Amazon will show us details of purchases, but they will not tell us any personal details about who bought them.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

## How We Store Information

If you opt in to our newsletter, tour information is stored at the list server that delivers those newsletters. Your information can only be accessed by those who help manage those lists in order to deliver e-mail to those who would like to receive this Site’s newsletters.

All of the newsletters or emails that are sent to you by the Site include an unsubscribe link in them. You can opt-out at any time from our newsletters or mailing list by clicking the unsubscribe link that can be found in every communication that we send you.

Otherwise, some of your demographic information may be stored within our Google analytics account. Don’t worry, though, this doesn’t include email addresses, names or any other personal information.

## Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

With respect to purchases, we do not store any payment details on this website, instead outsourcing that to a reputable and secure payment gateway.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

## Affiliated Sites

Through this website you are able to move to other websites, via links, and we have no control over the nature, content and availability of those sites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. These websites have established their own terms of use and privacy policies. We encourage you to read those documents as we have no control over their provisions and said documents may differ greatly from our terms and privacy policy.

## Affiliate Links

### What are affiliate links?

Affiliate links are a way for us to earn an income based on the honest reviews we provide on the website. An affiliate link directs you to a sales page on an external affiliate company website.  When a reader clicks on an affiliate link located on ThePodcastHost.com to purchase an item, the reader buys the item from the seller directly (not from The Podcast Host ltd.).   Amazon and/or other companies pay The Podcast Host a small commission or other compensation for promoting their website or products through their affiliate program.

Prices are exactly the same for you if your purchase is through an affiliate link or a non-affiliate link. **​You will  not pay more by clicking through to the link. **

### Our Affiliate Activity

Our main source of affiliate income is through Amazon.com.  The Podcast Host ltd. is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.  Amazon offers a small commission on products sold through their affiliate links. Each of your purchases via our Amazon affiliation links supports our cause at no additional cost to you.

If we link to an Amazon product (with a special code for affiliates embedded in the link), and a reader places an item in their “shopping cart” through that link within 24 hours of clicking the link, we get a small percentage of the sale.  Amazon links are not “pay per click.”  If you click on the product link and stay around Amazon and purchase something else, however, we will get commission on that sale.

 **Anytime you click a link that directs you to an Amazon website, then you can assume it is an affiliate link. Please rest assured, though, that we only link to products that we trust, either through personal experience or through strong recommendations from trusted parties.  **

## Children’s Information

Protecting the privacy of children is especially important to us. For that reason, www.thepodcasthost.com does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. If a parent or guardian believes that www.thepodcasthost.com has in its database the information of a child under the age of 13, please contact us immediately and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy or if you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please use the [contact form](https://www.thepodcasthost.com/contact-us/) for the Site. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
